It's Such a Beautiful Day is a animation, comedy
film directed by Don Hertzfeldt.
Bill struggles to put together his shattered psyche.
Narrator (voice), played by Don Hertzfeldt.
Doctor (voice), played by Sara Cushman.
It's Such a Beautiful Day is a 2012 American experimental animated drama film written,
directed, animated, photographed, produced, and narrated by Don Hertzfeldt.
It follows a stick figure who struggles with memory loss, surreal
visions, and other symptoms of an unknown neurological problem.
The film employs surreal humour and philosophical musings.
It mostly consists of stick figures with stylized real-life footage sometimes appearing
in split-screen windows that are photographed through multiple exposures.
The film is divided into three chapters, all of which were originally released in theaters as animated short films:
Everything Will Be OK (2006), I Am So Proud of You (2008), and It's Such a Beautiful Day (2011).
The three short films collectively received over 90 film festival awards upon their original
releases, including the Sundance Film Festival's Grand Prize for Everything Will Be OK.
In 2012, the three chapters were combined and released as a new feature film.
It's Such a Beautiful Day received widespread critical acclaim, with its experimental
storytelling and surrealist elements being singled out for praise.
Many listed it as one of the best films of 2012, and it has since come to be
widely regarded as one of the greatest animated films of all time.
The film explores themes of nightmare, immortality,
narration, dark comedy, surrealism.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and thought_provoking.